你真不愧为罪恶克星      谢谢
You did it again - thank you
教授，每场官司这样打下去，迟早会…
professor, you keep taking these big case,
sooner or later...
对付那些无法无天的歹徒
I know. You have to do what is necessary
最好的办法就是不择手段
to deal with these low-lived scumballs
教授，你不觉得很危险吗？
but professor, can't you think it
might put your own life in danger?
养虎为患更加危险
True, but it's more dangerous
if they're out in society
你跟了我那么久，你迟早都要独立
One of these days you'll be on your own
你这次返香港我没有什么送给你
I don't have much of a gift for you
when you go back to hk
这本书会对你很有用的
but this book here should be useful to you
不要向罪恶低头
when you're fighting against crime
我不会令你失望的
I won't let you down
教授，小心
professor, look out
我们离开这里
Come on, let's get out of here
离开这里，走      神经病
- Keep it. Get out of this place, go on, go
- You're crazy
活该
Shit
小心
no. Look out
正经一点
Be serious
吃饭了，不要玩
eat, don't play
好波呀
good
怎么不听话呀？
Why don't you listen to me?
警察叔叔，你看
Officer, look
截住他
Stop him
B仔呀
baby
妈咪…
Mammy...
老板，那些东西搞掂了没有？
Boss, have you fixed everything?
搞掂了
Yes
OK
ok
夏先生
Mr hsia
法官大人，我刚刚接到医院来的报告
Your honor, I got a hospital report
我的控方证人梁二胜一家八口
the whole liang family, eight of them
已经全部证实死亡
had been murdered
由于梁二胜死了
Now my witness liang is silenced
我现在已经没有其他有有的证人
I have no other witness to testify against
指证这两位先生走私贩毒
these 2 gentlemen's drug-trafficking
谋财害命的罪行
& killings
他们又可以逍遥法外
so they can now be scot free
反对，反对，反对
objection, objection, objection
反对有效
objection sustained
夏检控官，小心你的用词
mr hsia, watch your language
这本书所记载的，不单止是法律的条文
this book doesn't contain
legal articles alone
它还应该代表社会的正义和人类的尊严
they also represent social
justice & human dignity
但是它现在开始接受了挑战
but it is now being challenged
反对，法官大人
objection, your honor
我认为夏检控官
I think mr hsia's wasting
在浪费我两位当事人的宝贵时间
my clients' time
反对有效
objection sustained
你长话短说吧
cut short your speech
我老师曾经对我说，法律是人写出来的
my teacher told me that man made the law
当它一旦失去主持正义，维护尊严的时候
when it doesn't uphold righteousness
就应该有人出来面对罪恶的挑战
someone should stand up to challenge crime
反对
objection
法官大人
your honor
不用反对了
no objections are needed
本席宣判押后至7月14日再度聆讯，退庭
the hearing is adjourned to July 14
COURT
court
谢谢
Thank you
怎么样？夏检控官，又无罪释放？
How's it, sir? Acquitted again?
控方证人被人杀了
The prosecution witness has been murdered
证人死了，怪不得周鼎光…
no wonder chou ting-kuang
刚才在门口指着我鼻子说
pointed at my nose
想尽办法拉我好了，我后台有很多律师
challenging me to arrest him
夏检控官，法律究竟是保护市民
mr hsia, does the law protect
还是维护不法之徒
the citizens or outlaws?
我会亲自证明这东西
I'll try to prove this personally
明知犯了法也判不到他有罪
Don't you feel sorry being
你不觉得遗憾吗？
unable to sue the guilty?
遗憾可以解决问题吗？
Feeling sorry won't solve the problem
不过还是有办法解决的
there must be a solution
像这样子
照你们估计被告会不会有罪呢？
do you assume the defendants guilty or not?
不知道，不要碍着
No idea
一枪一个，好像打雀鸟一样，真痛快
I'll shoot them one after another
好，你这么有兴趣，我送枝猎枪给你
good, I'll send you a shotgun
再转行做律师，我替你辩护
then I become a lawyer to defend you
我老了，会手震
my hands tremble. I'm getting old
不如你来吧，到时我判你无罪
you do it, and I'll acquit you
你讲过要作算的
are you serious?
真聪明，叔叔送个公仔给你好吗？
You're clever. Take this doll
叔叔，你怎么知道我取到一百分呀？
how do you know I got full marks, uncle?
叔叔知道珠女乖，就买个公仔送给你
I know you're nice, so
ll've bought you this
叔叔，我请你吃雪糕
uncle, I'll buy you ice-cream
好呀
okay
爸爸给我钱
daddy, give me money
又说你请？去买啦
you promised to buy it. Go on
考虑得怎么样了？
what's your decision?
警方调查了他们三年
After 3 years' investigation
文件做满了八个抽屉
by the police
虽然没有人够胆出庭指证他们犯法
with documents piled up
但是有你一个出来指证
I'm 100% sure I can prosecute them
我有百分之一百的信心入罪他们
with you as the only witness
我一家八口，如果有三长两短，他们…
what if anything happens to my family of 87
不会有事的
you're going to be alright
放心啦，我保证
I assure you
先生，请你把球还给我
please pass me the ball, sir?
你叫什么名？
What's your name?
我叫肥仔
I'm fatty
叔叔，这里不可以停车的
uncle, you can't park here
警察叔叔会拉你的
or the police may sue you
谢谢你
thank you
拜拜
bye-bye
一家八口被你干掉，皇冠牌，你都算毒了
You're wicked, you killed at 8 members
看以后还有谁敢笃你两位大哥背脊
see if anyone dare to backbite you again
做得好，这些钱你收到没有？
well done. Have you got the money?
收到了，谢谢
Yes, thank you
那行了，有什么事我们再联络，拜拜
good, let's get in touch again. Bye-bye
只会伸手要钱
he knows nothing but asking for money
老卫，这买卖我们净赚多少？
wel, how much can we get on this?
一千万
$10 million
什么？一千万？
what? $10 million?
不是千五万吗？
Not $14 million?
五百万落了皇冠牌的袋里
The $5 million has gone to "crown"
老周，我们只求安乐
chou, it's worthwhile
这些钱不可以节省的
if we can live in peace
安乐的是他
he stands to gain
钱就会要，黑锅就不用他
he got the money without bearing the blame
害得我们在法庭上现世
but we are humiliated in court
早知道如此就用不着跟他合伙做了
we shouldn't have worked with him
算啦，如果不是他，我们还在吃皇家饭呢
we'd have still been in jail then
什么？要我们吃皇家饭
in jail?
如果我们吃皇家饭，到时他吃金银衣纸了
He'd have been in hell
老周，这里讲这里散好了
chou, don't say that in public
讲狠，皇冠牌比我和你狠
"crown" is much tougher than we
如果被他知道我们不合作，他会先郁我们
had he known we went against him,
he might have ruined us
郁我们？
ruined us?
现在讲郁，郁的是身家，不是胆色
你怎么说也好，凡事都是小心点好
Anyway, we must watch out
我回去搞掂那笔数目
I'll go and fix that amount
你通知兄弟们明天来拿钱
tell them to get the money tomorrow
老卫，你都要小心点呀
wel, you must be alert
卫先生
Mr wei
你两个在这里等我
Wait for me here, please
是
yes
老板出事了
The boss is in trouble
老板
Boss
撞！
crash!
老板
Boss
喂，周老板，我是阿洪
Hello, mr chou, this is hung
老板被人干掉了
the boss was bumped off
你听着，立刻拿这些钱来我家里
listen, bring the money to my home
是，我立刻来
yes, I'll come right away
七万
7-number
糟了，什么六也没有
Bad, no more 6-number
六万
6-number
兄弟，你有没有搞错？
what's the matter with you?
明明是四万，你说是六万？
It's 4-number, not 6-number
我说六万就是六万
I said 6-number
是你说六万的，我碰
you said it. I take
你现在当我是聋哑还是失明呀？
don't take me for a nut
只是六万也不足够，是什么位呀？
6-number is not enough. What position?
东风东位
East
我不管你中风，总之这只是四万
anyway, this is 4-number,
不是六万
not 6-number
不要吵，我食糊
quiet! I make
食糊？诈糊就有你的份儿
make? Stop dreaming
CID
cid
官字两个口，你说食糊就食糊啦
okay, a police officer has the say
师姐最大，你说什么就什么好了
yes, madam
大水牛
Buffalo
走开，不要碍着我发财
keep away! I'm gambling
我大水牛打牌的时候是戒色的
and I keep away from sex when I do
通常够胆揭我底牌只有两种人
only 2 persons can see my hole card
一是我老婆，一是我契家婆
my wife and my mistress
你只不过是鬼婆
you're only a caucassian woman
差婆又怎么样？
What's so special being a female cop?
我告诉你，这里是麻雀馆
Listen, this is mahjong school
不是差馆
not a police station
在公众场场所不要乱拔东西出来
Don't draw wantonly in public
师姐，看清楚环境才好动手呀
madam, take it east
鬼婆向来踢窦，双眼永远有前无后
when I come to storm, I never turn round
我怎么会向后望这三个擦鞋仔呀？
I won't turn round to look
at you apple-polishers
听到没有？师姐说你们是擦鞋仔
she calls you apple-polishers! Hear that?
还不替师姐擦鞋？
Polish her apple now
师姐，锁得这么厉害，当心你的晚年
Madam, be gentle. It's
good for your old age
阿SIR，是他们
they did it, sir
别动
stay where you are!
是他们四人，拉他们吧
They did it. Take them
起身
stand up
一个手铐锁四个人
one pair of handcuffs for four
师姐，汪SIR急电要你回去
madam, mr wang called to see you
知道了，替我拉他们回去
good. Take them for me
告他们企图谋杀，贩卖毒品
book them for attempted
murder, dope-pushing
袭警拒捕，掳人勒索，还有…
assaulting, kidnapping and...
还有？还有什么？
And what?
面目可憎
They look disgusting
拉他们回去      好
take them back - yes
你都算衰了
you're damned
走吧
get going
好呀，正呀
good, good
小弟初来此地，小小的东西不好意思
I'm new here. Only a small thing
这件你的
this is yours truly, help yourself
吃吧，不用客气
help yourself
吃吧，很好呀
eat. It's nice
师姐，吃一件后才打字吧，不用那么心急
madam, eat. Forget your work now
怎么你吃得这样不干净呀
you've made such a mess
很好吃的
it's palatable
住在哪里？家里电话几号？
where do you live? Your home number?
阿SIR，不要告诉我老婆呀
Don't ever tell my wife, sir
这么怕老婆你又干？
why are you so henpecked?
师兄，让我表现一下
Brother, let me
表现还表现，请你把手拿开
take your hand off me, please
你搞掂他
you fix him
坐那边
sit over there
看看你激得阿SIR这么不高兴
look, you've made him mad
哀什么呀？
what's your charge?
非礼
Indecent assault
非礼？很平常的
it's quite normal
非礼什么人呀？
how did you do it?
摸一下鬼婆的屁股而已
I caressed the ass of a foreign girl
什么？鬼婆？
what? Foreign girl?
鬼婆的屁股你也要摸？
How could you do such a thing?
罕有嘛
It's rare
罕有？大笨象也是罕有
rare? Elephants are rare too
香港只有一只，你又不去摸？
there's only one in hk
街上那么多中国女人你不摸，摸鬼婆？
why did you choose to
do that to a foreigner?
你都算种族歧视了
You must be racially prejudiced
她有什么好呀？
why did you do it?
我以为她不会叫非礼嘛
Because she can't shout in Chinese
不会叫非礼的你就摸
I see
你做人真没有原则，这不过是鬼婆嘛
you have no scruples
你自己看看，红毛就绿眼，卷毛就勾鼻
look, green eyes, curly
hair and hooked nose
我对他说你很美丽
I say to him you're beautiful
还有呀，腰粗就屁股大，肚腩就大过胸
and she has a big waist and big potbelly
远看似番薯，近看像棵大树
she looks like a tree at close range
还有满面雀斑，没有品味
and she has freckles and no feminine touch
我说你有品味
I say you've good taste
谢谢
thank you
手似熊掌，脚似…
her hands are like bear
palms, her feet are...
似龙船
Like a dragon boat
不错，似龙船
yes, like a dragon boat
原来你懂的
so you understand Chinese
告诉他我是谁？
tell him who I am
打散仔的当然是帮办
a tough one must be an inspector
你也会被人打的吗？
so even you got beaten
别吵      走开
- quiet!
- Keep away
你知不知道你衰什么？
do you know what's wrong with you?
哀什么呀？
What?
哀勤力呀
You're working too hard
是吗？
is that so?
去了哪里？找了你大半天了
Where have you been?
我去了查案，阿SIR
Working on a case, sir
我知道，难道你偷懒吗？
I know you're hardworking
我想告诉你一个好消息
listen,
卫成昨晚被人杀了
wei Cheng was murdered
真是个好消息，到底是谁做的好事？
good news. Who did it?
照理应该是鬼打鬼，黑吃黑
Must be a double dealer
不过身为警务人员
a policeman must round up anyone
就算杀人的是罗宾汉都一样要捉
even if he were a Robin hood
真矛盾
what a mockery
没有矛盾，这件案交给我做
let me take it over
你当然是首席人选
you're the best choice
不过今次我想多派一个人帮你
but I'll bring you an assistant
阿SIR，你也知道
you know,
我一向做事不喜欢找人帮手的
I never need help, sir
我看不用了
that won't be necessary
仙蒂，这件事不是那么简单
Cindy, it's not a simple case
我怕你应付不来
I'm afraid you can't handle it alone
阿SIR…
sir...
不要说了，就当是命令吧
Well, this is an order
好啦，这个人就让我自己去找吧
okay, let me find him then
这么近也掷不中，你的眼界不是这么差吧
you aimed badly
对不起
sorry
不用客气      对不起
never mind - sorry
对不起，MADAM
sorry, madam
不用对不起
how long have you been
你告诉我你在警界做了这么久
in the police force?
有什么事迹可以说出来威风一下
Have you done anything remarkable?
MADAM，到现在为止我仍是怀才不遇
Madam, I've still not won recognition
那就是无料到，对吗？
no one has recognized you?
是
No
由今天开始，你跟我办事
As of today, you work for me
YES，MADAM
yes, madam
我看起你是因为你没用，走吧
don't think I admire your talent. Get going
收工去喝茶
Let's have tea after work
站着
stand there
你做什么？
what is it?
做什么？看你的样子像烂仔，还吸烟
You look like a hooligan. You're smoking
这里不准吸烟的，知道吗？
no smoking here, understand?
够了
Enough
过来，过来
come here, come here
干什么？
what is it?
不要多说话，我知道你袋里一定藏有香烟
Quiet! I know you've
cigarettes in your pocket
把袋里所有东西拿出来
show me everything
老兄呀
brother
快点
hurry up
我知道你又是…
I know you...
干什么？
What is it?
穿鞋不穿袜，头发蓬松
You look haggard, disheveled hair, no socks
你看看，须又不剃
look, you need a shave
是不是不整洁也有罪呀？
is it an offence to be untidy?
你还驳嘴，信不信我打你？
Don't talk back. I may use force
够了      岂有此理，你…
enough - outrageous, you...
1750      YES，MADAM
1750 - yes, madam
让我来介绍，这位是我的新拍档
this is my new colleague
MADAM，不用介绍了，我认识他三十年了
madam, I've known him for 30 years
三十年？你今年三十二岁了，哀仔
30 years? You're already 32, bastard
两岁之前你没有见过爸爸吗？
didn't you see your father before 2?
原来你们是俩父子
So you're father and son
是
yes
话是这样说，是真是假他才知道
but he knows better
你个哀仔
you're damned
老兄，你想收买人命吗？
are you trying to kill?
当心车呀，哀仔
Watch out, son
我会，爸爸
I will, daddy
名牌车呀
a famous brand
MADAM，去哪里？送你一程好吗？
where are you going, madam?
I'll give you a lift
不用了，我一向不习惯坐这么名贵的汽车
I'm not used to such a limousine
找苦来辛是没罪的
it's not guilty to walk
守你这地头都不错
you must be okay
有这样的名牌的保时捷
to have the Porsche
人家有个好爸爸
you also have a daddy,
你也有一个，不过穷一点
but a poor one
MADAM，他很蠢的，你要教教他呀
madam, he needs your guidance
危险的工作不要让他做
don't give him any dangerous mission
因为我只有一个儿子
he's my only son
好，你放心，危险的工作我会打头阵的
don't worry, I know
谢谢
thank you
爸爸，你整天都是这么嗦
daddy, what a nagger you are
有空叫他多读点英文才行
he must learn more english
你做什么？
What are you doing?
跟你办事
To work for you
不用了，上面又高，风又大
no, it's windy and high
无谓要你爸爸担心
your dad may worry
留在这里看守车辆，这里最安全了
it's safer to watch the cars here
什么事？
what's it?
我是皇家师姐，带我上去看看
I'm madam. Take me up to have a look
好，你跟我来
okay, follow me
这个天台很大的
this roof is big
这是冷气喉，电梯机房在那边
the air-conditioning duct
the engine room's over there
电掣房在那边
the switch room is over there
那边是太平梯，我带你去看看
over there is the exit. Let me show you
等一等，师姐
wait, madam
自己人
a friend
什么自己人？我跟警察是世仇
what? I ate police
师姐，不用神气，大不了把车驶开
madam, at worst I'll drive away
我抄一张牌是11秒，你自己会该怎么做了
it takes me 11 seconds to ticket you
等一等，挞了火没有？驾驾执照呢？
Wait, have you started?
Your driving licence?
无牌驾驾？
Driving without a licence?
有呀
I have a licence
是临时的
A provisional one
明天就考，还有二十四小时
I'm taking the driving test tomorrow
师姐，我一定合格的
I must pass for sure, madam
你这么说即是希望我给你一次机会？
you want me to give you a break?
是
Yes
你没希望了
I love to
我这个人最喜欢落井下石，赶尽杀绝
kick dying people
不要，大家都是打皇家工
we're both civil servants
你不是想多给我一张吧？
are you going to give me one more”?
够了
Enough
希望你以后不会再遇见我
don't let me see you again
叫你看守车子一会儿也会被人抄牌
So you got ticketed so easily
你不觉得惭愧吗？
do you feel ashamed?
师姐，渔翁撒网，避无可避
Madam, I can't help it
你自己看看吧
see for yourself
好，调查一下他的身世
Well, let me check his background
读书多真的会坏脑子
Overstudying makes you a moron
想用法律令我坐牢？
trying to use law to put me in jail?
不用脑子去想想
Remember,
我的江山是用拳头打回来的
we got everything with our fists
老板，不如让我去教训他，让他知难而退
boss, let me teach him a lesson
有钱就连拳头也不用自己动
money makes the more run
找别人来干掉他
get someone to do it
是
yes
我要他能吃不能睡，能坐不能走
I'll make him a cripple
你记住，再有下一次，我就不再担保你
next time I can't bail you out
让你入感化院了
to get you into a reformatory
行了，北斗星，你的爱心和真诚打动了我
north star, you've touched my heart
我从此做个好人了
I promose to turn over a new leaf
你要说得出做得到才好
do you really mean it?
你这么苦口婆心，浪子也回头了
I've decided to turn over a new leaf
好，有救，知道自己是浪子
good
说得对，醒目仔
right, you're smart
你的女朋友？
your girlfriend?
做那一行呀？
What do you do?
检控官
A prosecutor
我不想讲再见了，两位慢慢谈，拜拜
excuse me. Bye-bye
他有两次偷窃案底
he has had two previous convictions
幸好我只有一次
luckily I only have one
你偷了什么？
what have you stolen?
偷心
A heart
今天你伤心了
excuse me,
我有很多工作做，没有空陪你
I'm busy
就是他
it was him
拜拜      拜拜
bye-bye - bye-bye
跟近一点
keep closer
行了，小姐我一定搞掂的
no problem if it's a girl
是麻甩佬呀
it's a male
麻甩佬？
a male?
师姐，是公事还是私事呀？
Madam, is it official or private?
无论是公事还是私事也好
In any case, tell me
试过他的身手之后一定要回来告诉我
after you've tested him out
快点，不然追不上了
hurry up before it's too late
辗死他，辗死他
Kill him, kill him!
有没有搞错？叫这么多人来打人？
Trying to outnumber him?
师兄，不用这么重手呀
Brother, not so hard
你看清楚才打好吗？自己人呀
stop! A friend
自己人？
a friend?
不要动
Stop!
警察呀，走吧
Police! Run!
不要走，不要走
Stop, don't run
你走？
are you running?
不用追了
They're only
这班人只是人家出钱他们出命的
hired hitmen
兄弟，你做过什么阴功事
did you offend
弄到成班人追斩你
someone to get his?
甚至我的鬼婆上司都正在调查你
Even my foreign lady
superior is probing you
查我？
is she?
你上司是谁？
Who's your superior?
讲起她真是了不起
She's really outstanding
最近卫成被杀那案件都是由她负责的
she's in charge of wei Cheng's murder case
这案件我也有份的
I'm also working on the same case
你有份？
are you?
检控官
Prosecutor
有什么需要帮忙的话，随时打电话给我
if you need any help, just call me
好呀
okay
拜拜
bye-bye
糟了，忘记了打他一顿
bad, I forgot to beat him up
回去怎么向鬼婆交代呢？
how am I to report back?
还被人打到周身肿，一定会被爸爸责骂了
I may get the hell from daddy
爸爸，轻力一点
daddy, lighter
轻力一点不能散瘀的
I must do it hard to cure you
知你瘀就瘀了，但不知你瘀得这么犀利
I didn't know you were so badly bruised
来吧，来吧
come on
不要胡搞呀
don't foul up things
觉得痛呢，以后不要那么冲动
next time don't be so impulsive
不要随便跟人打架
don't fight anymore
爸爸，是MADAM大力压下来嘛
daddy, madam is pressing hard
臭蛋，苹果
bad egg, apple
拿回来，拿回来
get it back
你什么时候才成人呀？
you never grow up
不好意思
sorry
成人？爸爸，你也到退休的时候了
daddy, it's time for your to retire
退休？你养我吗？
retire? Are you going to support me?
臭蛋，这个问题可大可小，不要随便乱答
It's a serious question.
Think before you answer
儿子养爸爸，怕什么可大可小呀
what is it so serious?
有粥就吃粥，有饭就吃饭
We'll live for better or worse
爸爸，对吗？
is that right, daddy?
算你识讲
Yes
借个火用一用
lend me a fire
哀仔，又说戒了烟？
I thought you'd given up smoking
看见你吸我又心瘾起了
only because you've turned me on
这么多心瘾，又不见你有向上爬的瘾？
why don't you work yourself up?
整天吊儿郎当
Why are you always loitering around?
爸爸，我整天都以汪警司为目标的
I've set my mind on a police superintendent
那你的目标太高了
don't set too high a standard
以你的资历怎样去做警司呀？
you don't qualify for it
知子莫若父
like fater, like son
仆街仔
you're incorrigible
喝杯酒吧
have a drink
每一个人都要对自己所做的事负责
one must be responsible for what one does
做人要清醒一点
be sober
多喝酒会容易令人不清醒的
drinking may be harmful
我现在很清醒，知道你说什么
I'm sober now. I know what you mean
你今天来找我，究竟想说什么
what did you want to see me for?
夏令正，你很喜欢玩火车的？
Hsia ling-Cheng, do you like trains?
是
Yes
我喜欢火车前进的大无畏姿态
I want to be dauntless
和我做人的原则一样
like a racing train
对，你应该知道
it's not
火车前进的第一个原则不是大无畏
dauntless
而是循规蹈矩
a train races on the right track
火车一旦出轨就会车毁人亡
once derailed, it kills
火车本身不会出路轨
a train doesn't derail by itself
除非有人刻意破坏
unless someone does it purposely
火车一旦被破坏，将会有很多人无辜受害
once destroyed, a train kills innocents
我的职责就是要拘捕那些破坏路轨的人
my duty is to arrest the destroyers
我的职责跟你一样
mine is the same.
如果有任何人破坏路轨
If anyone disrupts the rail,
我也不会袖手旁观
I won't stand by
维护法律的正义和公平
safeguarding justice
的确是一个冠冕堂皇的口号
is a beautiful slogan
不过我想没有人用这个口号
no one will
去做出一些破坏法律的事
use it to destroy
只要令火车安全到站
I'll do all I can to eliminate saboteurs
我会不顾一切尽全力去铲除破坏路轨的人
to ensure the train arrive safely
火车可以冲红灯
a train can't break out
但是不可以冲出我的手掌
of my palm
吃东西，吃东西
eat, eat
又吃东西？
again?
可以吃就不要浪费
Don't waste it
香港政府付钱，不吃就笨了
it's public money anyway
你吃尽管吃，师姐叫我们看守着这个人的
madam told us to watch this man
你千万不要背黑Z
don't ever get into trouble
背黑镬？
get into trouble?
我守了好几个钟头了，酒席也散了
I've been here for several hours
人家吃鱼翅，我们捱汉堡饱
the party's over, and
we're eating hamburgers
吃吧
eat
老板，我们先走了
Boss, excuse us
有没有搞错？吃饱就睡，真没你办法
Going to bed after eating?
什么事？
What is it?
咖喱，追呀
Curry, follow them
快点
hurry up
为什么挞不着呀？
why can't it be started?
我不知道      下车看看
- I don't know
- Get out and have a look
师兄，被一个苹果塞住了
brother, it's choked by an apple
回去一齐背黑镬了
we must bear the blame together
周鼎光，我不是拿你很多钱呀
Chou ting-kuang, you didn't pay me much
也不少了
quite a lot
对你来说就小儿科
it's kiddy stuff for you
数簿怎么样呀？拿出来吧
how's the book? Show me
你发神经呀
are you out of your mind?
连数簿也交给你，以后我还可以出来h食
How can I get on without it?
我给钱你用，你的痛脚就被我揸
Because I paid you, I have something on you
现在卫成被人杀了，我又被人控告
now wei was killed and I got involved
我告诉你，如果等会儿上庭我不掂的话
if I go wrong in court
你不要以为可以没事了
you won't
我一定拖你在一起的
be free either
如果连你也死去呢？
what if you should die?
我成班兄弟等着我开饭
My men live on me
我肯，他们都不肯
they won't let this happen
周鼎光，富贵险中求
chou, nothing ventured, nothing gained
求不求得到就要讲实力了
you need real strength
现在正邪的势力都被我掌握到
now I control the good and the evil
没有人可以再阻止我想做的事
no one won't be in my way
你…
you...
你班兄弟在下面等着你开饭呀
Your men are waiting below
叫啦，大声一点叫啦
Shout! Louder!
救命，救命…
Help, help...
周鼎光，你安息了
Chou ting-kuang, may you rest in peace
一会儿就会在法庭相见的
He'll be in court in a minute
这么早到被告家里干什么呀？
why did you come to the defendant's home?
夏令正，你还有什么话说？
Hsia, what have you to say?
这个时候我说什么也没有用
It won't do any good to say anything now
希望你冷静一点调查清楚
please calm down an investigate it
我想他怎么样也不会是自杀的
I don't think it was suicide
夏检控官，今次你水洗也不清了
mr hsia, now you can't clean yourself
走
get going
你千万不要出蛊惑呀
Don't try any tricks
就算出蛊惑也逃不掉的
you can't get away anyway
夏令正，你今天哀梗了
Hsai ling-Cheng, you're finished for sure
夏令正
Hsia ling-Cheng
活该
Shit
法官大人
Your honor,
由于本案次被告未能依时出庭应讯
since the defendant falls to appear
我代表控方要求充公被告的保释金
he should be under arrest
同时通缉被告
with bail forfeited
法官大人，我要求再多等十五分钟
your honor, I ask for
the grace of 15 minutes
我相信我的当事人已经赶来
I believe my client will rush here
你们不用等了，他永远也不会来
No need to wait. He'll never turn up
他已经被人杀死了
he has been killed
法庭之内不得宣哗
Silence in court!
你是什么人？
Who are you?
法官大人，我是重案组的高级督察施丽宜
I'm senior inspector shih li-yi of cid
希望法官大人批准我当庭拘捕
please Grant me permission, your honor
杀死周鼎光的疑凶夏令正先生
to arrest mr hsia who killed chou
施督察，你的要求被批准
inspector shih, your request is approved
夏先生，请你伸出手来
mr hsia, your hands please
等一等
wait
首先你有没有充分的证据
have you sufficient evidence
怀疑夏先生犯法呢？
against mr hsia?
否则本席可以告你妨碍审讯的程序
We can prosecute you for disruption
藐视法庭
and contempt of court
法官大人，我亲眼看见夏先生在凶案现场
your honor, I saw mr hsia on the spot
夏先生并且拒捕逃走
he resisted arrest and fled
如果真是这样子，夏先生就有可疑了
mr hsia is a suspect then
不过施督察，你会不会认错人呢？
but inspector shih, you
must've misidentified
我绝对不会认错
I did not
你为什么可以这样肯定呢？
how could you be so sure?
我可以理直气壮的问夏先生一声
I may ask mr hsia frankly
一个钟头前你在哪里？
where were you an hour ago?
你答我，你在哪里？
Answer me. Where were you?
答不出了
You can't answer
夏先生，我现在正式拘捕你
mr hsia, you're under arrest
一个钟头前，我和夏先生共进早餐
I was having breakfast
with mr hsia an hour agon
法官大人
Your honor
施督察
inspector shih
我很欣赏你办事的干劲
I admire your efficiency
不过你可能认错人了
but you're mistaken
所以请你不要阻止审讯的进行
please don't disrupt the court
否则本席会下驱逐令，并且向你提出起诉
or you'll be expelled
法官大人
Your honor,
这件案的两个被告既然相继死去
since both defendants have died
我要求撤销控告
I request the charge be withdrawn
本案就此审结
the case is closed
COURT
court
我真不明白为什么法官会把你释放？
I don't know why your were acquitted
不过不要紧，他放了你
but I can shoot you to death
我现在也可以一枪打死你
all the same
要就快一点，不然交通灯一转
faster, or I'll drive away
我就开车走了
when the light turns
开车呀
Go
八婆，开车呀
Go, bitch
死八婆，路是你的吗？
bitch, don't hog the street
失恋呀？被男人抛弃呀？
disappointed in love? Jilted?
看什么？
Keep away
死八婆，你以为有枪就了不起呀
Bitch, a gun is not everything
开门，开门，有人追斩我
Open up! I'm being pursed
快点开门
open up
开门
什么事？      先让我进去
- what is it?
- Let me get in first
不要乱开门，有人追斩我
don't open the door. I'm being pursued
文仔，干什么？      MISS
- wen, what is it?
- Miss
有人追杀我，你替我顶住先
resist for me, please
什么事情？
what happen?
余志文，你干什么呀？
Yu chi-wen, what are you doing?
MISS，这里真好环境
Miss, you're okay
早知我也多读书去做检控管了
I should've become a prosecutor myself
你怎样知道我住在这里？
how do you know I live here?
阿SIR，蛇有蛇路，鼠有鼠路
I have my eyes and ears, sir
香港有多大呀，要找一个人很容易
Hong Kong is only a tiny place
何况以你阿SIR的身份，找不到你？
any you're a man of status
昨天也遇见你啦
I saw you yesterday
你昨天看见什么      你昨天见过他吗
- what did you see yesterday?
- Did you see him yesterday?
你不用紧张，我不是说他
Don't get excited, I didn't mean that
我在说昨天我去找朋友
I mean when I arrived,
到达的时候他已经死了
he was dead
那我看见了就急急忙忙的走了
then I rush out
说时迟，那时快，突然间有枝枪…
suddenly, a gun...
枪指向额上
Pointed at my temple
我当然好汉不吃眼前亏
so I hastily...
一个擒拿手…
Grasped his hand...
扔掉他的枪
And flung away his gun
你说你没有杀人，谁人杀人你看不看见？
did you see the killer?
我就看不见
No, but that kid
不过下的臭小子应该看见的
under the table did
如果我找他出来做证，那就沉冤得雪了
with him as witness, the
record can be cleared
不过他不肯白白出来做证
but he won't agree to appear as witness
他还要照顾一个瘫了的阿爷
he has to look after a crippled grandpa
今天是我和女朋友相识两周年纪念
it's inconvenient to talk now
有什么事改天再谈吧
let's talk some other day
对，对，我没理由这么不识相
right, I should have thought about it
你这么识相，就拿去好了
take this
CID，站着
Cid, stop!
别跑
Stay there!
臭小子，听到CID就走，好人有限
贼人也常常说自己是CID
Even a thug calls himself 'police'
看清楚我是不是CID？
look at my identification paper
你的样子像贼多一点
you look more like a villain
说我的样子像贼，面向墙，靠墙呀
face the wall, lean against it
这一千在哪里得来的？
where did you get this?
是我的朋友夏检控官给我的
My friend prosecutor hsia gave it to me
是吗？他为什么要给钱你呀？
did he? Why did he give you money?
什么？不一定要你说
You may choose to speak
回警察局才说吧，走
at the station
你再认清楚一点，杀人的凶手是不是他？
look closely. Is he the killer?
阿姐，我对你说了很多次，是白狗呀
I said many times it was somebody else
黑狗偷食，白狗当灾的白狗呀
but he was framed
臭小子，你不要再耍阿姐了
how dare you tease me, kid?
MADAM
Madam
不关你事，继续写口供
not your concern. Take the statement
你不要跟我说什么黑狗白狗
stop making fool of me, kid
我告诉你，我不理你说什么狗
just take a close look
你最好认清楚一点
is he
当时杀人的到底是不是他？
the killer?
阿姐，你这样子，叫我怎么样认人呀？
How can I identify this way?
那是不是容易认一点呀？
Is this better?
阿姐，你这么恶干什么呀？
Sister, what are you doing?
我认出是人情，认不出是道理
I have no obligation to identity
我不是生出来认人的
it's not my duty to identify
你们要是再串的话我就向投诉组投诉
no more nonsense. Or I go to complaints
不用在这里受气
instead of getting the hell from you
臭小子
bastard
起来
Stand up
施督察，对付小孩子用不着这样套取资料
inspector shih, that's
no way to treat a child
这小子到过现场，我猜他看见夏令正杀人
he was one the spot, I
guess he saw the killer
是吗？
did he?
小朋友，跟我来
Little friend, follow me
你想怎么样？
what do you want?
不要紧张，跟你聊聊
Take it easy. I only want to have a talk
这里是警察局，只要你合作，没事的
if you co-operate, you'll be alright
小子，拿了成人身份证没有？
Kid, have you got an adult I/d card?
没有
No
那么醒目一定有命拿的
You'll live to get one if you're smart
这里是警察局，你不要乱来
this is police! Don't try anything!
他给你多少钱这样做呀？
How much did he pay you to do that?
我这样做不是为了钱
I didn't do it for money
没有好处你都肯做？
without money?
我只是为了义气
I did it out of justice
义气值多少钱一斤呀？
what price is your justice?
说出来听听
Tell me
你想放钱在我的袋里，我没理由拒绝的
I have no reason to turn down your gift
醒目
you're smart
小子，我像你这么大也没有你这么醒目
I wasn't that smart when I was your age
不用把高帽子给我戴了
apple-polishing
高帽子没有大用的
can't sell
对，讲得有道理
right you are
我这个人很有义气
I'm a man of righteousness
受人钱财替人消灾，那你怎样看法呀？
whatever I take I'll pay you back in kind
好，那义气值多少钱？
well, how much do you want?
不用口震的，尽量说吧
Just name it
一百万
one million
这么狮子大开口，当心啃死呀
aren't your afraid of getting choked
可以吃就不要浪费是我做人的宗旨
I have good digestion,
I can stomach anything
阿SIR，是不是可以立刻拘捕夏令正呀？
can you arrest hsia ling-Cheng, sir?
小朋友，对MADAM说声对不起
Little friend, say sorry to madam
MADAM，对不起，我不对，我乱说话
sorry, madam
我想搏取奖金嘛
I wanted to get a reward
我要告你报假案
我还未成年的
I'm not yet of age
我可以告你说谎的
I can sue you for lying
说谎有罪的吗？
is lying guilty?
臭小子      施督察
Bastard - inspector shih
小子，走吧
go now, kid
MADAM，我先走了
excuse me, madam
仙蒂，我们有很多工作要做的
Cindy, we've lots of things to do
小孩子报假案的事小儿科啦
let's not waste time
无谓浪费人力物力
on this
你回去工作吧
go back to work
臭蛋，快点去跟着这个小子
Bad egg, follow this kid
MADAM，我这份口供还未落完呀
madam, I haven't finished
taking the statement
你写了这么久，你写了什么呀？
what have you taken down?
黑狗偷吃，白狗当灾，灾字我不会写
I don't know how to write this word
你有没有搞错，灾字也不会写
you don't know who to write "framed"
你一定是没有当过灾
you must have never been framed
上边是水，下面是火，水火成灾
this
这样子也不会
will do
去跟着这个小子，不要甩拖呀
Follow this kid now
YES MADAM
yes, madam
太保，替我搞掂它
fix it
我去跟踪那个小子
I'll follow that kid
小心呀，衰仔，又被师姐骂了？
did you get the hell from madam again?
爸爸，不要骂骂声
Don't say that, daddy
师姐委以重任
I got an important
叫我跟踪那个小子，不简单的
mission from her
那就落足眼力，不要让他走甩
be smart, don't let him get away
行了，我跟踪，你放心
you may count on me
吃鸡脾吧，给包烟我吸吧
take this drumstick.
Give me a packet of cigarettes
衰仔，烟吸得多没有益的
smoking is bad for health
就这样子吧
that's all
对不起，师姐
sorry, madam
不好意思
sorry
爸爸，我先走了
daddy, excuse me
赶着去投贻吗？
rushing to hell?
讲错说话
Damn, I shouldn't have said that
给我捉到就要你的命
I'll kill you if I see you again
阿爷，我回来了
grandpa, I'm back
Grandpa, I'm back
阿爷，开门啦
grandpa, open up
我回来了
I'm back
阿爷
grandpa
Grandpa
阿SIR，你算怎么样？我和你已说好了
sir, why are you backing out?
你快放开我的爷爷
Let my grandpa go
你再不放开我阿爷
free him,
我把你的丑事全爆出来
or I'll blow the lid off your scandal
阿爷，阿爷，你不用怕
grandpa, don't be afraid
阿爷
grandpa
阿SIR，你想杀人灭口就杀我好了
Kill me, sir, if you want to
我爷爷什么也不知道，他是个哑巴
he knows nothing. He's mute
杀我啦，你杀我爷爷没用的
killing him won't do you any good
是我看见你杀人，不是我爷爷看见你杀人
he didn't see the killer, I did
阿爷
Grandpa
我跟你拼命
I'll fight with you
汪SIR，我想不到是你
Mr wang, so it's you
你干什么？
what are you doing?
汪SIR，你放了他吧
Mr wang, release him
你不要乱来
don't do anything foolish
把枪放下
put down your gun
文仔，快点走
Wen, run
大声公，我跟你捉几盘棋
Let's play chess
什么料呀？叫我到荒山野岭来
Some cheek! Why bring me here?
柴爷      柴爷
Mr tsai - mr tsai
mr tsai - mr tsai
怎么样子呀？干什么呀？
what do you want? What are you doing?
柴爷
Mr tsai
干什么？有说就说，不明白就问
speak up. Ask if your don't understand
不然留下我们的老家伙在这里干什么呀？
why let us old fellows stay here?
早就可以退休了，对吗？
We should have retired, right?
你真的要进去？柴爷
Are you sure you want to get in?
我看不需要了吧
Don't get in
神神秘秘干什么？
why are you acting sneakily?
那就是白头人送黑头人
An old man attending a young one's funeral
一会儿怎样对他说呀？
how are we to comfort him?
什么呀？千万不要说废话
Don't talk such nonsense as
什么节哀顺变，人死不能复生
don't be sad, etc
这些都是多余的，只会令人心烦
this is superfluous
我什么也不会，只是会说这几句嘛
I don't have anything better in mind
来了
coming
整天不停的嚷着叫我退休
you kept telling me to retire
幸好我不听你说
luckily I did not
不然谁养我呀？
or no one would support me
牛高马大，结果比我先去
you were strong, but died young
不要伤心了
don't be sad
节哀顺变啦，柴爷
don't overgrieve, mr tsai
人死不能复生，什么都是天意的
you can't go against heaven's will
谢谢汪SIR
thank you, mr wang
阿蛋这个人平时做事是糊里糊涂点
he normally muddled through
不过他很有上进心
but he was ambitious
汪SIR，他时时都找你来做目标的
mr wang, he always followed you as model
我知道，你不说我都知道
I know
他是一个好警察
he was a good policeman
你们俩仔爷都是好警察
both you and he are
每一个好警察都应该知道邪不能胜正
every policeman should know evil
can't conquer good
胜利永远属于正义的一方
justice always wins
我知道
I know
不要再哭了
don't cry anymore
我不哭
I won't
我不哭，我不哭
I won't cry
叫你穿上袜子的
I told you to wear socks
爸爸不是太反对你吸烟的
I didn't object to your smoking
后面有他的地址，干掉他
The other side has his address.
Finish him off
喂，喂
Hello, hello
来吧
Come on
come on
来吧
喂，请汪精卫警司
Hello, police superintendent wang, please?
我是，谁呀？
Yes, speaking. Who's it calling?
律政署的夏令正
Hsia ling-Cheng of justice department
有人来我家想杀我
someone tried to kill me at my home
真的？现在情况怎么样？
how's it now?
杀我的人死在我的家中
My killer died at my home
请你不要移动现场任何东西
please don't move anything from the spot
还有，他可能是杀死梁二胜全家的凶手
he may be the killer of the liang family
我立刻赶来
I'll come right away
好，我等你
okay, I'll wait for you
你不要相信他，他是杀人凶手
don't believe him, he's the killer
你说什么？谁是杀人凶手？
what? Who's the killer?
汪警司，刚才和你通电话的江警司
Sir, he just had telephone
conversation with you
他杀人？
did he kill?
他杀什么人？
Whom did he kill?
我看见他杀了周鼎光
He killed chou ting-kuang
还想杀我灭口
and tried to kill me to
destroy the evidence
你说的是真话？
are you speaking the truth?
为什么你也不相信我？
Why don't you believe me?
不是为了你的清白，昨天我就不会来找你
I came yesterday to prove your innocence
如果我不是在警察局里
I told that foreign lady
对鬼婆说你没有杀人
you didn't kill
汪精卫怎么知道我看见他杀人呀
so wang knows I saw him kill
就是因为这样子，他要杀你灭口？
is that why he tried to
kill to destroy evidence?
还有，他杀死了我爷爷
And he killed my grandpa
是我累死了我爷爷
I got my grandpa involved
阿爷，阿爷…
grandpa, grandpa...
糟了，我还打了电话给他
Bad, I even called him
这里很危险，我们快点走
it's dangerous here. Let's get out at once
你两个不要动
Stand there
原来是你
so it's you
是不是汪精卫派你来杀我们的？
did wang send you to kill us?
没有人派我来
No one did
如果我可以杀你，我已经一枪打死你了
I could've gunned you down if I wanted to
夏令正，杀人填命
hsia, you are linked with
你杀了臭蛋和小孩子爷爷
the death of bad egg
你是永远走不掉的
and that child of grandpa
你说是我杀死他们？
you accuse me of killing them?
不是，我爷爷不是他杀死的
No, he didn't kill my grandpa
阿SIR也不是他杀死的
he didn't kill the cop either
是哀警司杀的
that damn police superintendent did
你不要过来，不然一枪打死你
keep away, or you'll die
你不要乱来      别动
- don't do anything foolish
- Stay where you are
这个手铐你应该会用的
you know how to use the handcuffs
将你和小孩子锁在一起
handcuff yourself and that child
如果有什么蛊惑，我绝对不会客气
if you try anything, I'll be nasty
文仔，不用怕，我们跟她回警察局
don't be afraid. Come
with her to the police
不会有事的
you're going to be alright
我不去，你们警察没有一个是好人
no, I won't. There's not one good policeman
别走
stay
他只不过是个子孩子，你也不放过他？
he's only a child. Let him go
进来
Come in
汪SIR，夏先生要见你
mr wang, mr hsia wants to see you
叫他进来
show him in
YES，SIR
yes, sir
夏先生，请
mr hsia, please
你好，夏检控官
hello, mr hsia
对不起，我不知道你戴上了手铐
sorry, I didn't know you were handcuffed
YES，SIR
yes, sir
你想见我，不知道有什么事？
why do you want to see me?
我想看看人和禽兽有什么分别？
What's the difference
between a man and a beast?
我也正在这里看着
I was watching here
其实真的没有什么分别
there's not much difference
一样有眼有耳有口有鼻
both have eyes, ears and nose
有分别，禽兽通常多了一条尾巴
but a beast has a tail too
而且迟早也会露出来
and will show it sooner or later
对，对，可惜有尾没有尾
right,
在法律上人人是平等的
but they're equal in law
好像杀人那样，无论杀人是好人还是坏人
a killer is the same,
whether he's good or bad
又无论被杀的是好人还是坏人
and whether the one he kills is good or not
总之一慨叫做杀人
he's called a killer at the same
杀人者，迟早都好像阁下一样戴上手铐
a killer will be handcuffed like you
你明白就最好了，汪警司
glad you understand police
superintendent wang
就算我戴上手铐
even in handcuffs,
都一样可以对付你这些禽兽
I can deal with you beasts
我明白，我早就明白，其你贵为检控官
I understand. As a prosecutor
在法庭上说一声就可以险暴安良
you can stand for justice in court
又何必扮成执法先锋
why take the risk
冲锋陷阵，很危险的
to go to the front?
相信法律，对法律有点信心吧
Have confidence in law
记住，邪永远不能胜正的
remember, evil can't conquer good
小子，这么喜欢做猎人
you enjoy being a hunter
去森林打雀鸟吧
shoot the birds
想打虎？几时干到你呀
you can never be a tiger-killer
阿SIR，我们控不控告他呀？
are we going to prosecute him, sir?
汪SIR，一线
Mr wang, line one
先听电话
take it first
喂
hello
汪警司，你最近做了那么多好事
how are you doing
身体怎么样呀？
after doing what you did?
怎么样呀？阿庄，很久没见
It's you John. It's been a long time
那么快就记不得我没关系
remember
记得那本数簿就行了
that book
我给钱你用
it records the money
你的痛脚就被我揸的那本数簿呢
I pay you
没理由的
impossible
你知道数簿在哪里吗？
you know where that book is?
你有什么好提议？
What do you suggest?
钱，不要还价，不要出蛊惑
Money. No bargaining and no monkey business
一百万，今天下午海滨公园见
$1 million
see you at the harbor park this afternoon
好，依你的意思
okay, agreed
先扣留他四十八小时
detain him for 48 hours
你尽量搜集资料去控告他
get evidence
没法可想的话才放他
don't release him unless necessary
YES，SIR
yes, sir
施督察，二线
line two, inspector shih
男朋友找到这里了
your boyfriend is here
谢谢
thank you
喂
hello
鬼婆，我有办法证明夏令正是清白的
madam, I can prove hsia's innocent
我今天约了你的警司给掩口费
I've an appointment with your police supt
你千万不要告诉他我打电话给你
don't tell him I called you
好，反正我很久也没有看过电影
okay, I haven't seen a show for a long time
那就海滨公园见
see you at the horbor park
嘉莲，现在这个子子在你左手边
Karen, he's on your left side
他戴着太阳眼镜
he wears sunglasses
听WALKMAN，穿着蓝色飞机恤粉红色袖
he's listening to walkman,
in jacket with pink sleeves
我看见了，老板
I've seen him now, boss
这小子很蛊惑的，小心一点
he's crafty. Be alert
放心，我不会令你失望的
don't worry. I won't let you down
好，祝你好运
good luck
趴下
Crouch down
别走
Stop
stop
趴下
Crouch down
文仔怎么样？
How's wen?
你自己看看
See for yourself
问他，你大声一点问他
Talk to him loudly
他或者会答你
he may answer you
他会告诉你
he'll tell you
这个社会是没有法律的
there's no law in this society
这个世界是没有正义的
there's no justice in this world
我们这班执法者是不值得他们信赖的
we law enforcers can't be relied on
你…
you...
一向以为自己大公无私
Consider yourself disinterested
我问你
listen
文仔的死你说由谁去负起这个责任
who's responsible for wen's death?
夏令正，你不用这么大声
Hsia ling-Cheng, not so loud
文仔的死，其实你和我一样都是很难过
both you and I feel sorry for him
我会搜集证据缉拿凶手归案
I'll gather evidence to bring
the criminal to justice
证据？
evidence?
文仔已经死了，这些算不算证据？
Wen's dead, is this not evidence?
如果等有证据才去对付汪精卫
How many more will die before
不知道会死多少人了？
we get evidence against wang ching-sei
我告诉你，我们的法律
our law is not to help
不是要来伸张正义除暴安良
seeking justice
而是来保护那些杀人不眨眼的杀人凶手
but to protect the cold-blooded killers
你知不知道？
do you know that?
夏令正，我告诉你，我比你更加疾恶如仇
Hsia, I ate crime more than you do
你以暴易暴的方法我都会做
I can fight violence with violence
而且我会比你做得更加彻底
and I can do it better
你等着瞧
just wait and see
汪精卫
Wang ching-wel
你不用躲了，出来
no more hiding, come out
出来，我找你呀，汪精卫
come out to face me, wang ching-wel
我知道你在这里
I know you are here
出来见我
come out to face me
你们听不到我讲话吗？你们是聋的哑的？
you heard me? Are you deaf and dumb?
汪精卫，你恶贯满盈
You've come to the end of your evil road
你老实对我说，汪精卫有没有到来？
Tell me frankly, is wang here?
带我去见他，走
Take me to see him
你迫我出来对你有什么好处呢？
It doesn't pay you to have forced me out
汪精卫，我不会放过你
wang, I won't let you go
这句话应该由我来说才对
I should say this myself
学人做英雄？
want to be a hero?
我告诉你，这个世界是很残酷的
Listen, this world is cruel
做英雄的收场就是这样子
a hero ends up like this
你连一个那么忠心，处处维护你的手下
You even killed a female assistant
你都竟然忍心下手杀死她？
who had been loyal to you
没有，我没有下手杀死她
I didn't kill her
你验验凶器有没有我的手指模？
the weapon doesn't contain my fingerprints
你调查看看有没有人证？
see if there's any witness
我还可以告诉你
I was having breakfast
我刚刚才跟法官一起吃过早餐
with the judge
来到看见她就已经这样子
she was lying there when I arrived
我想她是自杀的
she must have killed herself
这种谎话你也说得出
what kind of a lie is that?
这里不是法庭，无谓多讲
This is not the court. Don't argue here
夏检控官
prosecutor hsia
你和我一样都是杀人犯
we're both killers
只不过你当自己是替天行道，儆恶惩奸
you invoke the name of justice
而我就滥杀无辜，杀人灭口
while branding me as wanton killer
其实无论用什么藉口杀人也好
whatever the excuse for killing
依法论法，杀人者死，结果都是一样
the killer should be
held accountable before
不过今天没有人审判我们
but, no judge is trying either of us
是我们两个互相解决
we're talking the law into our own hands